Previously on Transformers Prime:
在上一集中
Bulkhead, prepare for departure.
隔板 准备出发
Rafael and agent Fowler will be your communication and transportation hub.
拉斐尔和福勒探员负责联络和进行传送
Who is fiercest among you?
谁是你们中的最强者？
I am Hardshell.
我是硬壳
You will retrieve something for me: Tox-en.
你要去替我拿回一样东西 毒能
You are carrying it? I thought that stuff was toxic.
你带着它走？那东西不是有毒吗？
Your spark is mine, Wrecker!
你的火种是我的了 救援队小子！
That's right, soldier. Come on home!
就是这样 大兵 回家吧
The Wrecker let me alive.
救援队小子留了我一条命
The last mistake he will ever make.
这是致命的错误
No!
不…
We got the Phase shifter, and we messed up Knock Out's face... Oh yeah!
我们拿到了相位仪 还刮花了击倒的脸… 噢耶！
Hey!
嘿！
Let me guess, you and Raf spend all your drive time listening to chip tunes.
让我猜猜 你和拉夫在驾车时听首席音调
Well, its been fun,
好吧 那很有趣
but I'm ready to get back to my regularly scheduled partner, Bulkhea... Ah!!!
不过我已经准备好回到老搭档隔板的身边…啊！
Bulkhead respond!
隔板 回答我！
Bulkhead?
隔板？
What happened?
发生了什么事？
Tox-en exposure, among other things,
暴露在有毒物质中
Bulkhead had suffered a complete systems failure.
隔板的系统全面故障
Hold on, toxic-en?
等等 毒物 还有？
Help me get him into the medical bay, now!
帮我把他扶进医疗舱 快！
No!
不！
If I hadn't gone to New York.
如果我没有去纽约的话…
There's nothing you could have done.
这与你无关
Hardshell sucker-punched the big lug while he was down.
是那个硬壳在背后放的冷枪
Who?
谁？
Some Insecticon, it doesn't matter.
某只机器昆虫 不过那不是重点
Point is, it's not your fault. You got that?
重点是这不是你的错 明白了？
Got it.
明白了
How is this possible?
这怎么可能？
Four relics, each within our grasp.
四个遗物本该唾手可得
And yet, only Soundwave has return with something other than excuse!
只有声波有所交代 而其他人只有借口
Tell me, Hardshell. What is yours?!
告诉我硬壳 你的是什么？
I have none, my lord. We failed to retrieve the Tox-En.
我没有借口 陛下 我没能找回毒能
But the green Autobot has been... terminated.
不过那个绿色的汽车人已被摧毁
Then perhaps this day is not lost after all.
那么这次并非一无所获
If that is true. It has been a while since anyone has extinguished an Autobot's Spark.
如果属实 那真是很久都没人熄灭过汽车人的火种了
Because it has been a while since an Insecticon warrior has been provided the opportunity to do so.
那是因为机器昆虫已经很久未得到机会去一试身手了
Really now? Because the bug under my recent command was utterly useless.
真的假的？ 我指挥的那些虫子可都是些酒囊饭袋
Enough!
够了！
Hardshell, are you certain the one called Bulkhead was exterminated?
硬壳 你确定那个叫隔板的已经被摧毁了？
By my very own hand, lord Megatron.
我亲手所为 威震天陛下
Yes, sir.
是的 长官
Turns out, highlights of your Big Apple adventure got caught on security tape.
原来是你们在纽约的冒险被安保摄像机拍下来了
The Pentagon needs me to run interference with the Mayor.
五角大楼让我去收拾残局
I tried to stall, but...
我想留下 但是…
Go where you are needed, Agent Fowler.
去你需要去的地方 福勒探员
There is nothing more you can do for Bulkhead at this time.
现在你对隔板无能为力
Keep me posted, Prime.
保持联络 擎天柱
I mean it.
我说真的
Wheeljack's on his way.
千斤顶正在路上
I can't believe you're giving up on Bulkhead already!
我真不敢相信你们已经放弃隔板了！
All I meant was Wheeljack and Bulkhead are close.
我只是觉得千斤顶和隔板关系很好
I thought he'd want to be here.
我认为他想来这儿
I know what you meant.
我知道你的意思
Miko, where are you going?
神子 你要去哪里？
Home! While Agent Fowler can still give me a lift.
回家！好吧 趁福勒探员还能让我搭个便车
She needs time.
她需要时间
Bulkhead is stable, for the moment,
隔板现在情况稳定
but I've had to induce stasis.
不过他需要静养
What's the damage, Doc?
伤情如何 大夫？
Bulkhead suffered massive trauma to his central neural conduit.
隔板的中枢神经系统损伤严重
I've watched you work, you're a maestro.
那什么还在工作呢 这方面你是专家
The Tox-En exposure has caused system-wide shutdown on a sub-micronic level.
与毒气接触 使他最微小的系统也大面积停机
I can't even begin to operate until Bulkhead regains some strength.
除非隔板能恢复一些元气 否则我根本无法开展手术
You gonna tell me who did this to him?
你是不是不打算告诉我是谁干的？
At the moment, I believe it is best to focus our attention on Bulkhead's recovery rather than revenge.
我认为比起复仇 眼下我们更应关注如何令隔板恢复
You do that.
这活儿交给你了
Wheeljack will most likely do something rash, you know.
你知道 千斤顶肯定会莽撞行事的
And I am not sure we could stop him if we wanted to.
可我不确定 如果他执意如此 我们能否阻止得了他
Where are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Going after the Con who hurt Bulkhead. You in?
去找伤害隔板的虎子 你加入吗？
I'm taking you back.
我送你回去
No, wait.
不 等等！
Kid, I get it.
孩子 我明白
You want payback, you and me both.
你想以牙还牙 你和我想的一样
Bulkhead is my partner, too.
隔板也是我的搭档
Trust me, when I find out which one of Megatron's goons jumped our boy,
相信我 威震天那个害惨我们大男孩的手下 一旦被我找了出来
I'll take care of him... my way.
我会让他尝尝…我的方式
I know who did it.
我知道是谁干的
Who?
谁？
Take me and I'll tell you.
带上我 我就告诉你
You should have seen the Wrecker's face as his Spark expired,
你应该亲眼看看雷霆救援队的火种被熄灭
knowing that he perished at the hand of a true warrior.
他知道自己死在了一个真正的战士手中
Lord Megatron now understands
威震天陛下现在明白了
that the difficult tasks are best assigned to an Insecticon.
艰巨的任务最好分配给机器昆虫
Pit-bound scavengers.
恶臭的食腐者
Scrap eaters.
吃垃圾的
What did you say?
你说什么？
Detailing was so much easier when Breakdown was around.
这种小事若打击还在的话要简单的多
What is going on out there?
这是怎么回事？
How am I supposed to concentr... AH!
我要怎么…啊！
I just buffed that!
人家才打磨过的！
You know where to find Decepticon mines?
你知道在哪里能找到霸天虎的能量矿？
You didn't think I've just been sitting on my can since I've been on this rock?
你以为我到这颗小石头球上 是来混日子的？
But shouldn't we be at an Insecticon hive?
你确定这是一个霸天虎的虫巢？
The bugs are bound by a single mind.
机器昆虫由一个整体意识联在一起
Trying to draw just one of them out is nearly impossible,
想从中找出一个个体几乎是不可能的
so we're gonna make some noise.
所以我们要弄出点动静
And get the Cons to hand over Hardshell.
然后让虎子们交出硬壳
Now, you can sneak in there and scope things out a lot easier than I can.
你溜进去探查情况比我要容易得多
We got five, maybe six troopers in the main cavern
在主矿区有五至六个机械兵
and two more keeping an eye on things from the second floor.
上面还有两个负责放哨的
Good job, kid. Keep going.
干得好 孩子 继续前进
There's another chamber.
还有一个舱室
Looks like they're just using it for storage.
似乎是他们的仓库
Wheeljack, you there?
千斤顶 你在吗？
Now what?
现在怎么做？
We give Megatron a shout.
我们给威震天一个惊喜
Just look what they've done.
看看他们做了什么？
Spare me the dramatics, Knockout.
少跟我装相 击倒
It's merely a scratch.
不过是些小擦伤
This isn't about me, Lord Megatron.
这不仅是我的个人问题 威震天陛下
The Insecticons are creating dissension among the ranks.
机器昆虫在队伍中制造混乱
These savages are a threat to this warship and its crew.
这群野蛮人对战舰以及船员都构成了威胁
They should be confined... restrained, even!
他们必须受到限制与约束！
You could not produce restraints strong enough to hold us!
你可拿不出什么强劲到足以限制我们的措施来
Lord Megatron.
威震天陛下
We're receiving an emergency transmission from mine TVC-15.
我们接收到一条来自TVC15矿区的紧急信息
What seems to be the problem?
发生了什么情况？
Unclear, my liege. The caller will speak only to you.
不清楚 君王 该通讯只有您能接听
What is it?
什么事？
Nice operation you got here, Megatron,
你这儿的工作不错啊 威震天
although, technically, you might say it's under new management.
不过你或许会说 现在它换了新经理
Wheeljack, the one who enjoys explosive devices.
千斤顶 人送外号爆炸千
What can I say, Chief? I'm uncouth.
我能说什么呢 老大 我生来如此
And right now, I'm sitting on top of one of your big, juicy mining ops.
不过我现在正在你一个矿藏丰富的矿洞上方
The loss of one asset is hardly a blow to the Decepticon cause.
损失一点资源对霸天虎的伟业造不成什么打击
Maybe, but I'm gonna keep on hitting them, one by one,
或许吧 不过我会一个接一个地摧毁它们
until you give me what I want.
直到你交出我想要的东西
And what, pray tell, would that be?
你想要的东西？
The Insecticon scum who tried to frag Bulkhead.
试图杀害隔板的机器昆虫渣滓
Tried?
试图？
Are you saying the Autobot lives?
你是说那个汽车人还活着？
He is bluffing!
他在虚张声势
Wouldn't bet on it. So, here's the deal.
要不要打个赌 听听条件吧
I'm gonna transmit the coordinates of my next target.
我将会发送下一个目标的坐标
If Hardshell cares to meet me there,
如果硬壳来见我
maybe he can save you from another loss.
他没准能让你避免另一场损失
And, Megatron, just in case you ever wondered what 3 tons of exploding Energon sounds like...
威震天 你想不想知道3吨的能量爆炸是否悦耳？
You allowed the Autobot to live?!
你没能杀死那个汽车人？？
Hmph! Bugs. Not all they're cracked up to be.
哼 虫子们干的活漏洞百出
Lord Megatron, I swear upon the Allspark,
威震天陛下 我对火种源发誓
the Autobot could not have survived his wounds!
那个汽车人受的伤绝对致命
Then you owe me a Spark.
你欠我一个火种
And if it's not the one belonging to Bulkhead,
如果不是隔板的那一个
it had better be Wheeljack's!
那就给我千斤顶的！
Maybe you ought to power down for a while.
或许你需要进入节电模式一会儿
I'm good.
我很好
He's gonna make it, right?
他会挺过来的 对吧？
No question, kid.
没问题的 孩子
Bulkhead's the toughest wrecking ball I've ever known,
隔板是我认识的最坚韧的雷霆救援队员
and Ratchet's a great Doc, the best.
小救是位好大夫 最好的
Yeah. There's no way Bulk would miss all the stuff we have planned...
没错 隔板没理由错过我们计划好的全部活动
car sledding, worldwide smash-a-thon. We've been making a list.
汽车滑行 环球大破坏 我都排在日程上了
Like I said, Bulkhead's too stubborn not to pull through.
就像我说的 隔板无比坚强 一定会挺过来的
I know it, and I bet you do, too.
我明白这点 我知道你也明白
I'm up!
我起来了
What's the plan?
该怎么做？
Kid, if anything happens to me, press this.
孩子 如果我发生了什么不测 按这个
I've preset the autopilot to get you back to Prime's base.
我预设了自动驾驶 可以送你回擎天柱的基地
What? No way!
什么？没门儿！
We had a deal.
我们说好了
You said I could help!
你说过我可以帮忙
And you did.
你确实做到了
But it ends here.
不过到此为止吧
This is my fight, too.
这也是我的战斗！
Sorry, kid, but Bulkhead's gonna wake up.
抱歉了孩子 不过隔板就要醒了
And he'll file off my rivets if you're not there when he does.
如果那时你不在 他会连我的铆钉都踢下来的
Wheeljack!
千斤顶！
You in there, bug?!
你在那里吗 虫子？
Thanks to your crippled friend,
感谢你那位废物朋友
I am all too familiar with your Wrecker tricks.
我已经习惯你们雷霆救援队的小把戏了
What's the matter, Hardshell?
怎么了 硬壳？
Not used to fighting a bot who hasn't been doused in Tox-En?
不习惯和没中毒的对手作战吗？
Talk during battle is a sign of weakness.
在战斗中谈话是弱小的表现
Only when you're too primitive to do two things at once.
那只能证明你过于原始 无法一心二用
Go for the grenade!
快去拿手榴弹！
Wheeljack!
千斤顶！
No!
不！
Go, kid. Get out of here.
走 孩子 快离开这里
Your Spark will now belong to Megatron.
你的火种将敬献给威震天陛下！
Nice work, kid.
干得漂亮 孩子
Wheeljack, run!!
千斤顶 快跑！
I thought I told you to hit autopilot.
我记得我告诉你按自动驾驶键的
Bad things happen to bots when I leave their side.
没有我罩着 汽车人总会碰上各种麻烦
Too many to pick off.
目标太多
I'll need something with a wider blast radius.
我需要使用爆炸范围更广的武器
But I thought you...
我还以为你…
I only carry one at a time.
我一次只携带一个
Welcome to the Wreckers, kid.
欢迎加入雷霆救援队 孩子
You did Bulkhead proud.
隔板会为你骄傲的
Then why don't I feel any different?
但我觉得这不会改变什么
Miko, you okay?
神子？你还好吗？
She's fine! Kid's a pro.
她很好 这孩子很专业
I wasn't talking to you.
我没和你说话！
How is he?
他怎么样？
Bulkhead will survive.
隔板会活下来
He may never be fully functional again.
但他或许永远也无法痊愈了
Miko, I don't think it's wise for you...
神子！我认为你还不能…
I'm... not sure I want to see Bulk right now.
我…我不确定我现在是否想见隔板
Not like this.
不想在这种情况下…
I'm never leaving you again.
我再也不会离开你了
The Autobot did this?!
这是汽车人干的？
No, my lord. It was... a human girl.
不是 我的陛下 是… 一个人类小女孩